## Starrika McCloud

Full Stack Developer (MERN)

(JavaScript MERN) Full Stack Developer with 3 years of experience programming, coding, building, and maintaining web applications. Relocating to and looking for roles in Dallas, TX.

My passion is in troubleshooting, executing tasks with precision, and giving meticulous attention to detail, always prioritizing the right approach over shortcuts. My goals are working with others to solve relevant daily issues, enhance any place I encounter and ensure I leave the place better than how I initially found it.

**SKILLS**: Troubleshooting, Programming, Research, Maintenance & Repair, Technical Writing, Customer Relations, Debugging, Inventory Management

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Shalom Ministry (Non-Profit) – Plantation, FL Full Stack Developer (Volunteer Remote)

Oct. 2022 - Present

Minimizing bug-fix ticket turnaround by 75%, utilizing Winston npm and Mongo

- Minimizing bug-fix ticket turnaround by 75%, utilizing Winston npm and Mongo DB to log errors to database.
- Maximizing company meeting slots by leveraging separated/organized/reusable code modules and snippets, to quickly edit demos; promotes simple/proactive debugging and refactoring.
- Improving client customer UI/UX experience by collaborating with design team using google meets/messaging.
- Integrating platform by developing an administrative client portal equipped with dashboard UI, invoice/receipts, and employee access.
- Expediting release time by using Netlify/Heroku/Railway to deploy functional demos for clients to preview.

# **Entrepreneur** McCloud Lighting & Tech Solutions (MTS) Lighting Technician/Designer

2013 - 2022

- Reduced company maintenance expenses by 25% by maintaining / repairing equipment and updating Rep plots/venue schematics.
- Scaled organizational network, installed signal repeaters, and extended data points, reducing tech install time and increasing technical rehearsal performance.
- Prevented interruptions and reduced damage rate by troubleshooting electrical circuits, signal connections, lighting software and intelligent lighting fixtures.
- Consulted potential clients on cost friendly and efficient equipment and options.

### Norwegian Cruise Line Holdings Ltd. (NCL)

2018 - 2020

Lighting Technician

- Reduced company material expenses by 15%, conducting inventory on item lockers.
- Reduced technician errors and equipment damage by creating incoming technician handover and technical documents. Documents increased technician autonomy and management performance.
- Advised and led technicians in troubleshooting, problem solving and programming within their venues, increasing technical functionality.
- Reduced damage and shutdown rate by troubleshooting electrical circuits, signal connections, lighting software and intelligent lighting fixtures.
- Reduced company maintenance expenses by maintaining / repairing equipment and updating Rep plots/venue schematics.

#### CONTACT

San Antonio, TX 78154 (609) 815 1154 Cybre3@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/starrika-mccloud github.com/Cybre3 starrika-mccloud-portfolio.netlify.app

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGE - JavaScript
STACK - MERN (MongoDB, Express, React.js, Node.js)

#### **SYSTEMS**

- REST API
- Cache
- GitHub | Git
- Netlify | Heroku | Railway | Render

#### **METHODS**

- Version Control
- OOP (Object Oriented Programming)
- Functional Programming
- TDD (Test Driven Development)
- Code Optimization

#### **ASSETS**

TypeScript | Redux | Firebase | jQuery Bootstrap | Tailwind CSS Three.js | React Three Fiber

#### **EDUCATION**

**Kingsland University -** Atlanta, GA Certification - Full Stack Development

Mercer County Community College - West Windsor, NJ Associate in Science Degree – anticipated May 2024 Entertainment Technology

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

NCL - TRAINING AND DEVELOPMENT CERTIFICATIONS

Crowd Management & Safety, Basic Safety, Personal Survival Techniques, Fire Prevention and Fire Fighting (Without Live Fire), Elementary First Aid, Personal Safety and Social Responsibilities, Security Awareness

#### **AWARDS**

#### 05/2019

**Norwegian Cruise Line (NCL) - Outstanding Team** Delivering exceptional service and successful operation

#### 10/2018 & 11/2019

**Norwegian Cruise Line** (NCL) - Vacation Hero Delivering exceptional service

#### 2016

**Entrepreneur - NJACT Perry Awards** *Nomination* Best Lighting Design